RAHUL JOSHI

Full Stack Engineer

rjoshi9000@gmail.com • 510-996-8371 • www.rahulpjoshi.com • www.linkedin.com/in/rahul-joshi-00/

I'm a full-stack engineer who is in his element when he can creatively solve problems. I'm a passionate and precise learner with a degree in electrical engineering, who is motivated by innovation, building/strengthening connections, and social good.

SKILLS

Technical: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React.js, Ruby, SQL, C++, Python, MongoDB, MySQL, PostgreSQL, PHP, Express.js, Mongoose, Rails, Node.js, Sass, Bootstrap, Docker, Git

Non-Technical/Soft: Agile Methodology, Interdisciplinary Collaboration, UI/UX Design, Problem Solving, Detail-Oriented Thinking, Team Management, Active Communication

ENGINEERING PROJECTS

TalenTree App: Individually implemented the React on Rails stack to create a twelve-page app that allows teachers to create one-on-one classes that students can browse and join.

Wine Community App: Collaborated in a team of four to build an eight-screen wine community app that was built on the MERN stack (MongoDB, Express, React, and Node) and lets users sign up to join a community of wine enthusiasts who recommend, rate, and review wine.

Networking App: Created a five-page app for people to post networking messages and get input via implemented voting system. Used project experience to polish React skills (ex. React hooks, React Router, etc.) and introduce a mock back-end with Airtable API.

Dance Program Website: Developed and administered a full website for an online dance program utilizing HTML, Sass, JavaScript, and Bootstrap to attract 50 new clients to program.

WORK EXPERIENCE

CS@SC Camps - Teaching Assistant & Content Designer (Remote) February 2021-June 2021

- Moderated and taught classes of 4-6 kids about web development (HTML/CSS) and Scratch.
- Individually designed and managed all content from promotional flyers to posts on organization's four social platforms (Facebook, Twitter, Instagram, and website), bringing in 80 new followers.

AgilePoint – Intern (Mountain View, CA)

May 2019-August 2019

- Built three automated applications incorporating REST API's, field mapping, and more to expedite client organization's data collection, analysis, and migration.
- Collaborated and relayed information to an international six-person design team during daily meetings to integrate front-end construction with back-end processes.

Relevance Labs - DevOps Intern (San Jose, CA)

June 2018-August 2018

- Produced a three-node proof-of-concept to demonstrate data center migration to cloud.
- Utilized Python to parse JSON/CSV files for Compute, Storage, and Networking information.
- Initiated meetings with two lead DevOps engineers to present testing results.

EDUCATION

University of Southern California

August 2017-May 2021

Bachelor of Science, Electrical Engineering

Los Angeles, CA

Coursework: Data Structures & Object-Oriented Programming, Discrete Methods in Computer Science, Internet of Things, Embedded System Capstone Design, Web Architecture

General Assembly

May 2021-August 2021

Software Engineering Immersive Certificate

Remote

LEADERSHIP & INVOLVEMENT

- Founded and co-directed The Corner Project, a 20-person dance team in Los Angeles
- Volunteer for Community Seva, a non-profit community service organization